<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Best Place to Code</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Best Place to Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aditi Pandit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/aditi-pandit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/aditi-pandit/</guid>
      <description>Aditi is a Principal Engineer at Ahana/IBM. She is a Prestissimo committer in the Presto and Velox Open source projects. Aditi has an extensive data infrastructure career of ~18 years at Google, Teradata Aster and Informatica before joining Ahana/IBM. She has a MS in Computer Science from Stony Brook University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akshay Ram</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/akshay-ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/akshay-ram/</guid>
      <description>I love to build technology products that help people live better lives.&#xA;Specialties : Product Management, Technology, User experience, Competitor analysis, Business Strategy</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albert Wong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/albert-wong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/albert-wong/</guid>
      <description>Albert Wong is a developer advocate at CelerData, a database company that is building StarRocks, a Linux Foundation project that aims to be the world&amp;rsquo;s fastest open source data query engine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Merced</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/alex-merced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/alex-merced/</guid>
      <description>Alex Merced is a developer advocate for Dremio and has worked as a developer and instructor for companies like GenEd Systems, Crossfield Digital, CampusGuard and General Assembly.&#xA;Alex is passionate about technology and has put out tech content on outlets such as blogs, videos and his podcasts Datanation and Web Dev 101. Alex Merced has contributed a variety of libraries in the Javascript &amp;amp; Python worlds including SencilloDB, CoquitoJS, dremio-simple-query and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ali LeClerc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/ali-leclerc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/ali-leclerc/</guid>
      <description>Ali has over a decade of experience in open source software, product, and community marketing. She was most recently Head of Community at Ahana, the SaaS for Presto company, which was acquired by IBM. She works closely with the Presto Foundation to drive open source programs. Prior to Ahana, Ali held community and marketing positions at Alluxio, Couchbase, and Time Warner. She holds a degree from Yale University in Political Science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrey Gusarov</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/andrey-gusarov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/andrey-gusarov/</guid>
      <description>Senior Data Engineer | Data Architect | Engineering Manager</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arthur Ansquer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/arthur-ansquer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/arthur-ansquer/</guid>
      <description>Product Manager and ClickHouse user for a handful of years. Based in Madrid, Spain. Now in charge of the Aiven for ClickHouse and Aiven for Cassandra at Aiven.io</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arul Jegadish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/arul-jegadish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/arul-jegadish/</guid>
      <description>Arul has extensive experience in building and managing open source based DevOps toolchains. OpsVerse, a company he co-founded, is into the business of making it easy for anyone to run OSS DevOps tools at scale.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avi Press</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/avi-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/avi-press/</guid>
      <description>Avi Press is the founder &amp;amp; CEO of Scarf. He is a leading advocate for better data-sharing initiatives in the open source community, in efforts to support maintainers and foster a healthier, more quantitatively-driven OSS ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beinan Wang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/beinan-wang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/beinan-wang/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Beinan Wang is a Senior Staff Software Engineer at Alluxio and a committer and TSC of PrestoDB. Prior to Alluxio, he was the Tech Lead of the Presto team at Twitter and he built large-scale distributed SQL systems for Twitter’s data platform. He has twelve-year of experience working on performance optimization, distributed caching, and volume data processing. He received his Ph.D. in computer engineering from Syracuse University on the symbolic model checking and runtime verification of distributed systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brian Bickell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/brian-bickell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/brian-bickell/</guid>
      <description>Brian is the VP of Strategy and Alliances at Cube. Prior to his work at Cube, he managed tech alliances at Firebolt and built the award winning data management business at the consulting firm InterWorks. Brian combines strong technical acumen and industry experience with his more than a decade of experience in data analytics consulting to approach the challenges facing the analytics practitioner with wisdom and empathy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cameron Cyr</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/cameron-cyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/cameron-cyr/</guid>
      <description>Cameron is a data fanatic who has spent his career developing data systems enabling valuable use cases such as analytics and machine learning. During this time, he has placed a focus on building reliable and scalable data systems with an emphasis on data quality. Cameron currently serves as a Staff Data Engineer for a vacation rental tech startup. He also is one of the organizers of the Nashville Data Engineering Group meetup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chris Hazard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/chris-hazard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/chris-hazard/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Chris Hazard is Howso co-founder and CTO. Howso&amp;rsquo;s understandable and privacy enhancing AI spun out of Hazardous Software, a company Chris founded in 2007 that focuses on decision support, visualization, and simulation for hard strategy problems in large organizations, DoD, and government. Chris holds a PhD in computer science from NC State, with focus on artificial intelligence for trust and reputation. He was a software architect of CDMA infrastructure at Motorola, worked on robot coordination and logistics at Kiva Systems (now Amazon Robotics), is an active member of the CompTIA AI Advisory Council, and advised NATO on cyber security policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cole Bowden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/cole-bowden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/cole-bowden/</guid>
      <description>Based in San Diego, Cole is the Release Manager and a Developer Advocate for Trino. He was introduced to the project as a software engineering intern at Facebook back when it was Presto, and has stuck with it since. When not working with software, he enjoys live music, baseball, and all things gaming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dipesh Mittal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/dipesh-mittal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/dipesh-mittal/</guid>
      <description>Dipesh has been building software for over 11 years across startups. He was head of engineering at a $500M company for 5 years before starting his own venture in monitoring space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dunith Dhanushka</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/dunith-dhanushka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/dunith-dhanushka/</guid>
      <description>Dunith avidly enjoys designing, building, and operating large-scale real-time, event-driven architectures. He&amp;rsquo;s got 10+ years of doing so and loves to share his learnings through blogging, videos, and public speaking.&#xA;Dunith works at Redpanda as a Senior Developer Advocate, where he spends much time educating developers about building event-driven applications with Redpanda.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evan Rusackas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/evan-rusackas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/evan-rusackas/</guid>
      <description>Evan is a Sr. Developer Advocate with Preset, Inc. and works closely with the Apache Superset community. He&amp;rsquo;s a front-end engineer, engineering manager, and designer. The design and building of data visualizations and user interfaces have been Evan&amp;rsquo;s key interests for over the last several years, but he now spends the bulk of his time growing and engaging with the Superset community, striving to improve the product and its processes along the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Felipe Mendes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/felipe-mendes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/felipe-mendes/</guid>
      <description>Felipe Mendes is an IT specialist with over a decade of experience working with distributed systems and databases. He has co-authored several technical publications, ranging from Linux, containers, distributed systems and distributed databases. A frequent speaker at events, he works as a Solution Architect for ScyllaDB.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gabor Szarnyas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/gabor-szarnyas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/gabor-szarnyas/</guid>
      <description>Gábor Szárnyas is Developer Relations Advocate at DuckDB Labs. He obtained his PhD in software engineering in 2019 and spent 3 years as a post-doctoral researcher at CWI in Amsterdam, working on graph data management techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gang Tao</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/gang-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/gang-tao/</guid>
      <description>Gang has over 20 years experience in software development, and is a recognized expert of AI, BI, Big Data and Data Visualization. He was the principal engineer of Splunk&amp;rsquo;s ML and Data platform. He&amp;rsquo;s also a die-hard fan of AC Milan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heather Meeker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/heather-meeker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/heather-meeker/</guid>
      <description>Heather Meeker is a General Partner at OSS Capital, www.oss.capital, an early stage venture capital fund specializing in commercial open source development. She is also a partner at Tech Law Partners, LLP, www.techlawpartners.com, a law firm focused on technology transactions.&#xA;Meeker is an internationally-known specialist in open source software licensing. Her book Open Source for Business, now in its third edition, is a definitive handbook for lawyers, engineers, and businesspersons on open source licensing in business.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jarek Potiuk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/jarek-potiuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/jarek-potiuk/</guid>
      <description>Independent Open-Source Contributor and Advisor, Committer and PMC member of Apache Airflow, Member of the Apache Software Foundation&#xA;Jarek is an Engineer with a broad experience in many subjects - Open-Source, Cloud, Mobile, Robotics, AI, Backend, Developer Experience, but he also had a lot of non-engineering experience - running a company, being CTO, organizing big, international community events, technical sales support, pr and marketing advisory but also looking at legal aspect of licensing and building open-source communities are all under his belt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javier Ramirez</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/javier-ramirez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/javier-ramirez/</guid>
      <description>I help developers make the most of their (fast) data, I make sure the core team behind QuestDB listens to absolutely every piece of feedback I get, and I facilitate collaboration in our open source repository.&#xA;I love data, big and small. I have extensive experience with SQL, NoSQL, graph, in-memory databases, Big Data, and Machine Learning. I like distributed, scalable, always-on systems.&#xA;Before working in Developer Relations, I spent 20 years developing software professionally and sharing what I learnt with the community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeffrey Nelson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/jeffrey-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/jeffrey-nelson/</guid>
      <description>Jeff has a background in data analytics and is passionate to enable developers of all abilities to use data to solve real-world problems. He enjoys blending storytelling with technology to teach analytics principles and practices to developers. Prior to Google, Jeff worked as a data engineer at a global systems integrator in the Media &amp;amp; Entertainment vertical, where he helped small and large companies gain value from their data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Tigani</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/jordan-tigani/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/jordan-tigani/</guid>
      <description>Jordan is co-founder and chief duck-herder at MotherDuck, a startup building a serverless analytics platform based on DuckDB. He spent a decade working on Google BigQuery, an engineer, book author, Eng and PM leader. More recently, as Chief Product Officer at SingleStore, he helped them relaunch their database as a service and grow it into a thriving business. His biggest claim to fame is predicting world cup matches with a better record than Paul the Octopus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jove Zhong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/jove-zhong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/jove-zhong/</guid>
      <description>Jove has over 18 years in enterprise software product development and management. He previously was an Engineering Director at Splunk, and holds 17 Patents and 4 AWS Certifications. He is a board sports fanatic, incl. agile board.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juan Luis Cano Rodríguez</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/juan-luis-cano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/juan-luis-cano/</guid>
      <description>Juan Luis is an Aerospace Engineer with a passion for STEM, programming, outreach, and sustainability. He has a decade of experience as developer advocate, software engineer, and Python trainer in several industries, and currently he works as Principal Product Manager for Kedro, an open source Python framework for data science, at QuantumBlack, AI by McKinsey.&#xA;He has made significant contributions to the PyData stack and published several open-source packages, the most important one being poliastro, an open-source Python library for orbital mechanics used at space agencies, satellite companies, and universities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Julien Jakubowski</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/julien-jakubowski/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/julien-jakubowski/</guid>
      <description>Julien Jakubowski is a Developer Advocate at StreamNative with over 20+ years of experience as a developer, staff engineer, and consultant. He has built several complex systems with distributed, scalable, and event-driven architecture for various industrial sectors such as retail, finance, and manufacturing.&#xA;Julien delivers talks at conferences on software engineering, specializing in the Java community: Devoxx, VoxxedDays, Berlin Buzzwords, Java User Groups, and Google Developer Groups, among others.&#xA;Julien is located in France.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jun Rao</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/jun-rao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/jun-rao/</guid>
      <description>Jun Rao is a co-founder of Confluent, a company that provides a data streaming platform based on Apache Kafka. Before Confluent, Jun Rao was a senior staff engineer at LinkedIn where he led the development of Kafka. Before LinkedIn, Jun Rao was a researcher at IBM&amp;rsquo;s Almaden research center, where he conducted research on database and distributed systems. Jun Rao is a committer of Apache Kafka and Apache Cassandra.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karin Wolok</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/karin-wolok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/karin-wolok/</guid>
      <description>Karin is the founder of Project Elevate, a DevRel consulting company. With a decade of experience in community programming, advocacy, and developer relations, Karin has built thriving communities that drive growth and engagement for companies across various industries. As Head of Developer Community at StarTree, Karin played a key role in bringing the company from 0-1 in developer engagement, marketing, community programs, recruiting, and culture development. She also led the community at Neo4j, where she built a thriving community that became one of the unique selling points of the product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ken Chen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/ken-chen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/ken-chen/</guid>
      <description>Ken Chen has over 14 years of enterprise software experience. He previously worked in AWS, Splunk and EMC and has deep experience in distributed systems, database and enterprise / cloud storage architecture design and development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenaz Kwa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/kenaz-kwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/kenaz-kwa/</guid>
      <description>Kenaz Kwa is the VP of Product and Design at FOSSA, a technology platform that helps organizations with open source license compliance, security, and SBOM management. Prior to joining FOSSA, Kenaz served as the Director of Product Management at Puppet, a DevOps leader in configuration management. Previously, he held several Program Manager positions at Microsoft on the Azure team.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyle Cunningham</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/kyle-cunningham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/kyle-cunningham/</guid>
      <description>Kyle Cunningham is a software engineer and user experience designer. He&amp;rsquo;s had a lifetime passion for technology that began with legos, taking apart electronics, and building computers. That passion has continued with over 15 years of professional experience in the tech industry, helping organizations all over the world make things easier, more convenient, and more civiliz</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mary Grygleski</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/mary-grygleski/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/mary-grygleski/</guid>
      <description>Mary is a Java Champion and a passionate Senior Developer Advocate at DataStax, a leading data management company that champions Open Source software and specializes in Big Data, DB-as-a-service, Streaming, and Cloud-Native systems. She spent 3.5 years as a very effective advocate at IBM, focusing on Java, Jakarta EE, OpenJ9, Open Source, Cloud, and Distributed Systems. She transitioned from Unix/C to Java around 2000 and has never looked back since then.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matt Harrison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/matt-harrison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/matt-harrison/</guid>
      <description>Matt teaches Python and Data Science. He has a CS degree from Stanford University. He is a best-selling author on Python and Data subjects. His books: Effective Pandas, Illustrated Guide to Learning Python 3, Intermediate Python, Learning the Pandas Library, and Effective PyCharm have all been best-selling books on Amazon. He just published Machine Learning Pocket Reference and Pandas Cookbook (Second Edition). He has taught courses at large companies (Netflix, NASA, Verizon, Adobe, HP, Exxon, and more), Universities (Stanford, University of Utah, BYU), as well as small companies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maxime Beauchemin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/maxime-beauchemin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/maxime-beauchemin/</guid>
      <description>Maxime Beauchemin is the founder and CEO of Preset, a series B startup supporting and commercializing the Apache Superset project. Max is the original creator of Apache Airflow and Apache Superset, the open-source projects he started during his time at Airbnb. Max has over a decade of experience in data engineering at companies including Lyft, Airbnb, Meta, and Ubisoft.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michel Tricot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/michel-tricot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/michel-tricot/</guid>
      <description>Michel is the co-founder and CEO of Airbyte, the leading open-source data integration platform that allows replicating data from any APIs, databases &amp;amp; files to data warehouses, data lakes, and any other destinations. Airbyte has been used by over 40k companies and has over 4k daily active customers. Airbyte raised $180M from Accel, Benchmark, Coatue &amp;amp; Altimeter.&#xA;Prior to starting Airbyte, Michel was a founding member &amp;amp; Director of Engineering at rideOS, and Head of Integrations and Director of Engineering at LiveRamp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nadine Farah</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/nadine-farah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/nadine-farah/</guid>
      <description>Nadine Farah is leading Onehouse&amp;rsquo;s developer initiatives. She&amp;rsquo;s passionate about bridging engineering, product &amp;amp; marketing to help drive product adoption. She previously led Rockset&amp;rsquo;s developer initiatives, focusing on building technical content to drive developer adoption for real-time analytics. At Bose, she contributed to the watchOS SDK &amp;amp; worked with partners to embrace spatial audio in the music and gaming industries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nick Schrock</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/nick-schrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/nick-schrock/</guid>
      <description>Nick Schrock is the founder and CTO of Dagster Labs, the company behind Dagster. Previously, Nick worked at Facebook, where he co-created GraphQL. Nick believes deeply in the power of well-designed developer tools to make engineers more productive, accelerate their careers, make their lives more enjoyable, and transform the organizations in which they work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pat Nadolny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/pat-nadolny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/pat-nadolny/</guid>
      <description>Pat is Senior Data Engineer at Meltano where he spends most of his time contributing to the Meltano open source project and its surrounding ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pedram Navid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/pedram-navid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/pedram-navid/</guid>
      <description>Pedram Navid is the Head of Data Engineering at Dagster Labs, and an avid birdwatcher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Zaitsev</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/peter-zaitsev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/peter-zaitsev/</guid>
      <description>Peter Zaitsev is an entrepreneur and co-founder of Percona. As one of the leading experts in Open Source strategy and database optimization, Peter has used his technical vision and entrepreneurial skills to grow Percona from a two-person store into one of the most respected open source companies in the business with over 350 employees. Peter now continues to serve as a board member and advisor to a range of open source startups.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robert Hodges</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/robert-hodges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/robert-hodges/</guid>
      <description>Robert Hodges is CEO of Altinity, an enterprise provider for ClickHouse data warehouse. He&amp;rsquo;s also a database geek with experience on at least 20 DBMS types. Robert caught the Kubernetes bug at VMware in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roman Shaposhnik</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/roman-shaposhnik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/roman-shaposhnik/</guid>
      <description>Roman is a co-founder of Ainekko: a 100% open-source company on a mission to democratize how “the machine learning community collaborates on models, datasets, and applications” and helping “the AI community building the future” have more choices than just a single (albeit awesome!) walled garden. He is a serial entrepreneur, technologist and a co-founder and former CTO of ZEDEDA Inc. who is also deeply involved in the world of Open Source as both VP of Legal Affairs at the Apache Software Foundation and a former VP of Technology at The Linux Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ryan Blue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/ryan-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/ryan-blue/</guid>
      <description>Ryan Blue is the co-creator of Apache Iceberg and works on open source data infrastructure. He is an Avro, Parquet, and Spark committer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sean Hughes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/sean-hughes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/sean-hughes/</guid>
      <description>Sean is the co-founder of Evidence, an open source business intelligence tool where all content is defined in markdown and SQL. Previously, he helped build the data team at a Canadian private equity firm, and uncovered several problems with BI tools which Evidence sets out to solve. He&amp;rsquo;s an analyst at heart and loves building things that make an analyst&amp;rsquo;s job easier and more fun.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shirshanka Das</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/shirshanka-das/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/shirshanka-das/</guid>
      <description>Shirshanka is CTO and Co-Founder of Acryl Data, the company driving the DataHub project. DataHub is used by companies like Peloton, Optum, Expedia, Klarna and many others. With the DataHub community, he is leading the charge on developer-led approaches for modern data discovery, quality and automated governance.&#xA;Over the last decade, Shirshanka has created foundational systems across operational, streaming and data warehousing ecosystems. While at LinkedIn, he founded the open source DataHub project and is also a PMC and committer on the Apache Gobblin project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Siddarth Jain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/siddarth-jain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/siddarth-jain/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m building Doctor Droid, an event analytics tool for monitoring purposes.&#xA;Previously, I was a full stack ML Engineer (Data Science models, ML models and Data engineering) at a leading hyperlocal startup where we delivered over a million food &amp;amp; e-commerce orders every day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timothy Spann</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/timothy-spann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/timothy-spann/</guid>
      <description>Tim Spann is the Principal Developer Advocate for Data in Motion @ Cloudera where he works with Apache Kafka, Apache Flink, Apache NiFi, Apache Iceberg, TensorFlow, Apache Spark, big data, the IoT, machine learning, and deep learning. Tim has over a decade of experience with the IoT, big data, distributed computing, streaming technologies, and Java programming. Previously, he was a Developer Advocate at StreamNative, Principal Field Engineer at Cloudera, a Senior Solutions Architect at AirisData and a senior field engineer at Pivotal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uma Maheswara Rao Gangumalla</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/uma-maheswara-rao-gangumalla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/uma-maheswara-rao-gangumalla/</guid>
      <description>Uma Maheswara Rao is an Apache Software Foundation Member[1]. An Apache Hadoop, Ozone, BookKeeper, Incubator committer and a member of the Project Management Committee[2], and a long-term active contributor to the Apache Hadoop project. He is also mentoring several incubator projects at Apache. He has more than 15 years of experience in large scale Distributed Software Platforms design and development. Currently, Uma is working as a Senior Engineering Manager at Cloudera, Inc, and primarily focuses on open source big data technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viktoria Ondrejova</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/viktoria-ondrejova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/viktoria-ondrejova/</guid>
      <description>Data Analyst Intern at Slido, currently pursuing a degree in Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zander Matheson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/zander-matheson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/authors/zander-matheson/</guid>
      <description>Zander is the CEO and Founder of Bytewax - a Python stream processing framework. His previous experience prior to Bytewax had been as a data scientist at GitHub and Heroku. He lives in Santa Cruz, California and when not at his computer likes to get outdoors.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
